# Jonathan Pires

Software Engineer

(978) 399.4889 · jonbpires@gmail.com · Ayer, MA · JonsPortfolio.com · LinkedIn · github

As a software engineer with experience as a lead contractor I am confident when it comes to delegating and training as I expand my own skill set. I take a lot of pride in my work and want people to associate my name with exceeding standards and making a good impact. I am confident in my full-stack development skills as well as my ability to lead and support peers through breaking down complex ideas.

#### **SKILLS**

**Programming Languages** - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Python | **Libraries and Frameworks** - React, Node.js, Express.js, Django

Database - PostgreSQL, ORM, MongoDB, Mongoose, ODM | Other - RESTful Routing JSON, AWS S3

Version control - git, github | Deployment - Netlify, Heroku

**Spoken Languages** - English | Portuguese | Spanish

### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

February 2023 - Present

#### Stack-Up | Full-stack web application | HTML, CSS, Node, Javascript, MongoDB, Heroku

- Built a full stack application in a week long sprint with full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations hitting all RESTful API calls. The app is a social platform for stock predictions. Where you can create posts and comment under them.
- Deployed to Heroku

# Trip City | Full-stack web application | HTML, CSS, Django, Javascript, PostgresQL, Heroku, AWS S3

- Built a full stack application where users can have a planner for their trips and also post about what they've done in each trip and make it available to other users, in a week-long sprint with full create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations hitting all RESTful API calls.
- Used AWS S3 Buckets to hold images from the Application and deployed to Heroku

### Shred | MERN-Stack App | MongoDB, Express, React, Node, Heroku

- Utilized React.js components for the front-end, creating an application that allows the user to create exercises and workout plans by adding exercises from the database and adding notes to each exercise within the workout.
- Made RESTful API fetch calls to an Express, MongoDB, Node.js backend handling all create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations.
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections.
- Implemented ES6 tagged template literals with Styled-Components along CSS3 and bootstrap to provide style and a responsive layout of the application.

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**General Assembly**, Software Engineer Fellow | Remote

February 2023 - May 2023

- Collaborated with teams remotely over zoom and slack to plan, design, and code full stack web application projects
- Developed competencies in Full Stack Development methodologies and modern tools and languages in a project based learning immersive
- Participated in daily standups and code reviews after developing ERDs to align with peers on expectations and planning
- Worked independently to conduct supplementary research for stylizing and troubleshooting errors
- Lead project management for development sprints; organizing and aligning a team of 3 developers ensuring detailed documentation and smooth github flow

NHR Construction, Freelance Home Improvement Contractor | Meriden, CT June 2018- December 2022

- Aligned budgets, style, and priorities with clients and designed and executed custom projects to meet specifications
- Oversaw a crew of 5 contractors, delegating tasks and organizing schedules to ensure a fast and high quality delivery
- Built and maintained relationships with over 70 residential clients

### Moura's Cleaning, Area Manager | Leominster, MA

November 2016 - May 2018

- Oversaw over 15 accounts and 20 employees, maintaining relations with customers and employees.
- Provided continuous training, actively hire employees to fill new accounts, maintain schedules and do book keeping.

# **EDUCATION**

### **GENERAL ASSEMBLY | REMOTE**